Kashaf Ashfaq

250 Manley Road Chorlton Manchester M21 0RD Tel: 01619179755 Mobile: 07427607741

Email: kashaf_92@hotmail.co.uk

Date of birth: 20/04/1992

SKILLS

Programming: Comprehensive understanding of an umpteen number of programming languages. More proficient with C# due to working as a c# developer for the past 5 years. I've worked on many applications and websites and I feel like I've truly honed my skills during this time.

Testing: I use TDD practices when coding. I make sure my solution has as much code coverage as possible. I do believe unit testing and integration testing is definitely something which everyone should adhered to because if you change or refactor a piece of code you could run all your unit tests and be satisfied this hasn't broken the application without having to regression test your whole application which could be timely.

Teamwork: I am able to work effectively within a team, productively contributing, listening, and absorbing team member's ideas and naturally bouncing ideas off my team mates. I have worked within a team all throughout my development career. I have become accustomed to practices such as sprint planning, sprint reviews, sprint retrospectives, and daily stand-ups. I also often partake in 3 amigos meetings which are held between a Dev, QA, and the BA to gain more clarification on a specification.

Problem solving: This is something I have learned to appertain to with it being a key inflicting obstacle whilst programming. It is only conventional to stumble upon problems whilst programming but I have learned to indentify, analyse, and solve by dissecting the problem to make it more comprehensible and essentially, simpler to solve. In general I am able to keep a cool head when faced with problems and solve accordingly. This practice has helped substantially in the past especially when writing code. I have been able to problem solve along with my team mates when producing solutions for a specification. This is something I have always done and as a result over the years I have nurtured problem solving techniques from my seniors and I'm sure I have passed on valuable techniques to my juniors.

EDUCATION

University of Salford

2010-2013

BSc (Hons) Computer Science (2:1) (Individual grades for relevant modules: 3D game

programming 74, .Net Services 64, Agile software Development 64, Entrepreneurial management 69)

Loreto Sixth Form College BTEC National Diploma in IT

2008-2010

3 Distinctions (Equivalent to 3 A's in GCE A Levels) 360 UCAS points out of a possible 360.

Chorlton High School

2003-2008

9 G.C.S.E's at A*- C Including English, Maths & I.T.

EXPERIENCE

Computer Design Systems

08/2013 - 03/2014

Software Developer

I held the position of a junior software developer at Computer Design Systems. My main duties were to work amongst the development team to develop and maintain commercial software for a wide range of clientele from oil distribution companies to the health care industry. I was successful on completing a project I was given, to develop an in-house software for the support team as well as implementing a new feature on an existing customer software.

Peninsula Business Services

04/2014 - present

C# Software Developer

Being in an IT environment for 5 years I have had the time to work with old technologies and then shift over and be exposed to the newer technologies. A good software developer should be able to adapt and accommodate to constant change this is something I have been able to do whilst working at Peninsula. The skills I've honed and the tech I've had exposure to over the past 5 years includes: VB.Net, ASP.Net Web forms and MVC, Angular JS, WebAPI's, NUnit, TDD, Entity framework, Nhibernate, SQL server, and many more. I have contributed thoroughly and helped deliver green field projects as a part of a team. I found myself in a situation where my senior had left half way through a project which only he and I were working on and I completed and delivered the project successfully on my own.

INTERESTS

I also have a keen interest in graphics design, from time to time I make flyers and posters for family and friends. I'm quite familar with the adobe suite. I also enjoy reading, my favourite novel is called 'Into the wild'. I love travelling and going on little adventures. I'm also a big foodie and thefore I truely appreciate good food. I love my sports, i'm big football fan. Enjoy watching and I play every fridays. I also play Squash every thursdays.

REFERENCES

- References available upon request.